<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.2.1">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2021-12-24T13:30:33-08:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Bootleg Batard</title><subtitle>Where we build community by nourishing neighbors</subtitle><author><name>Juliet Kelson</name></author><entry><title type="html">It is getting steamy!</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2020/05/05/steamy.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="It is getting steamy!" /><published>2020-05-05T20:45:13-07:00</published><updated>2020-05-05T20:45:13-07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2020/05/05/steamy</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2020/05/05/steamy.html">&lt;p&gt;Steam is essential for proper expansion of the dough, and for good caramelization of the crust.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A sure sign of a good bake is evidence that there’s plenty of steam in the oven. Introducing steam when loading the oven offsets crust formation, allowing the dough to fully expand. It’s also responsible for greater caramelization of the crust, thanks to increased enzymatic activity and creating ideal conditions for Maillard. Electric and gas deck ovens have steam injected with the press of the button. For our wood fired operation, we use a number of strategies, always including a garden sprayer. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In your home oven, introduce steam by putting a pan of 2 oz of boiling water on the floor of the oven just before loading. If you have a Dutch oven this isn’t necessary as the steam is trapped by the cover. You could jerryrig something from oven safe pans, but it won’t have the same effect of the retained heat of cast iron. Challenger Breadwear makes a cool pan that specially designed for bread-baking.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/img/posts/IMG_0571.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;Bread Loaves&quot; width=&quot;500&quot; height=&quot;500&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Although these two loaves were baked from the same dough, in the same oven, at the same time, the loaf on the left didn’t get steamed and therefore it looks matte, has less volume, a tighter crumb, and the crust is less richly flavored.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Juliet Kelson</name></author><summary type="html">Steam is essential for proper expansion of the dough, and for good caramelization of the crust.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Now What?</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2020/04/15/now_what.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Now What?" /><published>2020-04-15T20:45:13-07:00</published><updated>2020-04-15T20:45:13-07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2020/04/15/now_what</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2020/04/15/now_what.html">&lt;style&gt;
            ol li {
                font-weight:bold;
            }
            li &gt; p {
                font-weight:normal;
            }
.image-txt-container {
  display: flex;
  align-items: center;
  flex-direction: row;
  white-space: nowrap; 
  padding: 8px 0;
}
&lt;/style&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Settle in. This is a long post. Your starter is healthy and ready to work, but the recipes you find are really complicated and a little confusing, am I right? Just like you realized that your writing improves and follows a common progression with an outline, bakers use the same outline for all yeast dough production. And there’s room to improvise or riff in there too— I’ll explain.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But, before you get started, you’ll need some ground rules. Use grams and you and your kids can brush up on math.  I noted in an earlier post that bakers understand their formulas  by expressing them in percentages— this is really just a simple ratio. I recommend using a recipe written this way as it is an indication that it’s coming from a professional, and also, you will begin to see patterns. DON’T RESIST! The math will set you free, and it’s really easier than it seems.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p style=&quot;font-weight:bold&quot;&gt; 12 Steps of Yeast Dough Production &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Scaling&lt;/li&gt; Measure your ingredients, accurately, and on a scale. 
    &lt;li&gt; Mixing &lt;/li&gt; Optional step- &lt;span style=&quot;font-weight:bold&quot;&gt;autolyse&lt;/span&gt;. Here you combine all of your flour and your water together until you have a shaggy mass. Let this mixture sit for 20 minutes or up to a few hours. The gluten will unravel on its own, so less mixing is required. This preserves the carotenoids in your flour, retaining the color, provides a more extensible dough, and it ultimately increases shelf life by not oxidizing the dough. Then add your salt and carry on to true mixing. If you are using a liquid starter, it will need to go into the autolyse so you have enough hydration for your flour. If your starter is added, don’t let the mixture autolyse longer than a half an hour or fermentation will run away from you.
    &lt;div class=&quot;image-txt-container&quot;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;/img/posts/dylan_mixing.jpeg&quot; width=&quot;50%&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;h2&gt;
    &amp;nbsp; You can mix by hand or by mixer.
  &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you are mixing by machine, put your water on the bottom first. Add your starter (don’t forget to save some so you can bake again), flour(s) and salt.The goal of mixing is to distribute ingredients, develop the gluten, and bring the dough to the appropriate temperature (73-76￮F is common for lean doughs). I’ll talk about how you achieve that in another post. Your mixed dough should not look like taffy. In fact, the more you mix, the tighter your interior crumb structure will be. It’s better to gain strength to your dough through fermentation and folding. Put your dough in a lightly oiled or a wet bin. Cover it and keep it someplace between 70-75 degrees.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;li&gt;Fermentation&lt;/li&gt; So, technically this is happening until your yeast dies in the baking process, but there is time set aside just to let the yeast do its thing. What’s happening here? Yeast is converting complex carbohydrates into simpler ones. Like college students, it’s all about binging and reproducing. It’s gobbling up these sugars (which enzymes are breaking into small units so the yeast can consume it), and it’s expelling gas (carbon dioxide for lift) and alcohol (flavor). Its spores are also budding and splitting, creating more units of yeast. 
      &lt;div class=&quot;image-txt-container&quot;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;/img/posts/fermentation.jpeg&quot; width=&quot;50%&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;h2&gt;
    &amp;nbsp; You can see the gnarls of gluten &lt;br /&gt; &amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;in this just mixed dough
  &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It’s better to develop the dough through our next step, folding.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Folding&lt;/li&gt;&lt;p&gt;also called stretch and fold, or sometimes punching. Please don’t punch this dough you’ve so lovingly created. It’s alive, right? We all do better with gentle guidance. So, intermittently, you are going to stretch and fold the dough. This realigns the gluten strands, so they can lengthen and trap more gas. It also evens the temperature in the dough tub.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some tips, wet your hands and the dough will not stick to them. When you pick your dough up, think of lifting a cat under it’s arms. It should slump like a cat, allowing the dough to fold over on itself. I’ll post some video of this later. How many folds? Depends on the strength of the dough, which you will learn through practice. More folds means more strength, so there is too much of a good thing. I fold my sourdoughs roughly every 50-60 minutes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Dividing&lt;/li&gt;Here’s where you cut your dough into specified weights. Use your scale! 
&lt;div class=&quot;image-txt-container&quot;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;/img/posts/dividing.jpeg&quot; width=&quot;50%&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;h2&gt;
    &amp;nbsp; I try to keep my dough &lt;br /&gt; &amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;as uniform as possible
  &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Water or flour your work bench before stretching your dough into an even rectangle. Cut decisively with a bench scraper or knife.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Preshape&lt;/li&gt;Gently guide the closer to its final shape. This is an important opportunity to realign the gluten, so it can trap that carbon dioxide. Does your dough feel sticky? It’s likely because you are tearing the gluten and allowing the water the protein had been holding to leach out. Don’t do that! use a gentle touch.
&lt;div class=&quot;image-txt-container&quot;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;/img/posts/preshape.jpeg&quot; width=&quot;50%&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;h2&gt;
    &amp;nbsp; Think about using the &lt;br /&gt; &amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;flat pads of your fingers &lt;br /&gt; &amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;when you handle your dough.
  &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
Seriously, stop poking your fingers through it. You make it much harder for you when you’re tearing the gluten.
&lt;li&gt;Bench Rest&lt;/li&gt; You’ve done a lot to the dough in the last few steps. Back off! Leave your preshaped dough on a lightly floured surface, and cover it so a skin doesn’t form. You can use plastic wrap, but that never ever decomposes, so maybe use a tea towel instead, or reserve a sheet of plastic that you use over and over for this purpose. Just saying. Anyway, this step lasts 10-30 minutes, depending on how your dough is feeling. If it springs back during the next step, give it a longer break.
&lt;li&gt; Final Shaping&lt;/li&gt; Put the dough in the shape you intend it to be. I’ll get some process pictures for this  to update later.. Once the dough is shaped, you will put it between cloth (called couche, but you can use a tea towel) or in a basket (called a banneton or brotform, you can line a bowl with a tea towel if you don’t have).
&lt;div class=&quot;image-txt-container&quot;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;/img/posts/final_shaping.jpeg&quot; width=&quot;50%&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;h2&gt;
   &amp;nbsp;Loaves in brotform
  &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These willow baskets are dusted with rice flour and wheat flour to keep them from sticking, and add a design.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;image-txt-container&quot;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;/img/posts/batards.jpeg&quot; width=&quot;50%&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;h2&gt;
   &amp;nbsp;Bâtards on couche
  &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This cloth keeps the dough from sticking to each other, and the loaves snuggle together to help keep their shape.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;optional step: &lt;span style=&quot;font-weight:bold&quot;&gt;Retarding&lt;/span&gt;- So, at this point, you can cover the dough and chill it in your refrigerator for 8-12 hours. This allows you to take a nap and manage your schedule for convenience, and it gives the dough time to ferment slowly.  Doughs that have been retarded often have blisters on the surface (called fish eyes), that Americans love. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Proofing&lt;/li&gt;  This is a second designated period where you just let the dough form gas and expand. The length of proof is dependent on the quality of your fermentation. It’s variable, but for my sours, it’s usually 2-2.5 hours. I can check if it’s done by gently pressing (not poking!) my finger into the side of the loaf. If the impression holds, it’s done proofing. Keep the dough covered during this period.
&lt;li&gt;Baking&lt;/li&gt; Lots happens now. In lean doughs, you will need to score the dough. This cutting or slashing (which is only called scoring) allows CO2 to escape through predictable places. It’s also the baker’s signature. Use a razor (bakers use razors called lames) and cut quickly and decisively. As a rule, you want to have a balance across the surface in your cuts so the dough can open uniformly. 
&lt;p&gt; Is your oven preheated? Good. You’ll want to bake between 450-480￮F. Lots of home bakers are using Dutch ovens to bake. It’s a fantastic solution. I like the Challenger Breadware Pan, but if you have a Dutch oven, that works well. If you are baking this way, score your bread and load into your hot oven. Otherwise, you can jerry-rig your oven a bunch of ways! You can put firebricks or quarry tile on the bottom RACK of your oven, and load your scored loaf on there. The problem is you’ll need steam. In a Dutch oven, the steam is trapped around the loaf by the lid. If you’re reproducing a hearth with stone, I suggest you boil 1/4 of water and pour it onto a pan on the floor of your oven just before loading your scored loaf. Do not pour water or ice on the floor of your oven, unless you are looking for an excuse to buy a new oven. You’ll ultimately warp the floor of your oven. Just don’t.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Why steam? It offsets crust formation, allowing the dough to fully expand. Also, it creates the necessary conditions for Maillard, so your loaf will caramelize beautifully. It’s critically important for your success. Remove the lid of the Dutch oven, or crack the oven door and take out the pan (to be sure there is no extra steam) for the last third of your bake. This allows the crust to firm. Determine doneness first by time, second by color, and lastly by knocking on the bottom of the loaf. It should sound hollow.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Your dough will enjoy the largest rise during the baking process. This is called oven spring.  We can talk about what happens during this process at a later date.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Cooling&lt;/li&gt; Yeah, you can’t eat it yet. In fact, this step is critical to producing good bread. Let it cool, with good air circulation. Alcohol dissipates, the crumb sets, and your flavor from the crust gets pulled back into the loaf due to osmotic pressure. Don’t cut your hot loaf! Give it at least two hours to cool. Seriously. Some loaves “cure” for a few days before cutting.
&lt;p&gt;Cool it on a rack. If you leave it on your countertop or in a pan, it will condensate and get soggy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Storage&lt;/li&gt;Store your loaf in a brown paper bag at room temperature, or wrap in a clean tea towel. No plastic. What would happen if I wrapped you in plastic? You’d get sweaty, right? Lean doughs will never mold, unless you abuse them by putting them in a plastic bag, where the moisture it releases during the natural staling process, is trapped, creating mold. Gross. At room temp and in something breathable, it will merely dry in the days to come.
&lt;p&gt;And yes, you can freeze it. In this case, you would wrap it in plastic to protect it just before freezing. Defrost completely and then revive at 400￮ for 7-10 minutes before serving.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;</content><author><name>Juliet Kelson</name></author><summary type="html"></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Let’s Talk a Little More About Sourdough Starter</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2020/04/13/sourdough-starter.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Let’s Talk a Little More About Sourdough Starter" /><published>2020-04-13T20:46:13-07:00</published><updated>2020-04-13T20:46:13-07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2020/04/13/sourdough-starter</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2020/04/13/sourdough-starter.html">&lt;p&gt;It isn't just flour, water and yeast. In fact, one of the most important components growing in that gruel is the microflora-- a spectrum of lactobacillus bacterium, that gives unique flavor, acidity, increased shelf life, and greater digestibility to your bread. But is there too much of a good thing?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I like to think of yeast on one side of the seesaw, and lactobacillus on the other side. Too much yeast and you won't have as much acidity. Too much acid and the yeast becomes sluggish, producing too little carbon dioxide.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Control the yeast to lactobacillus ratio with proportion of &quot;seed&quot; starter that you dose your starter with in regular feedings, and by controlling temperature and frequency of feeding. Most important, taste and observe your starter fine tuning for the flavor you like. I prefer a mild-lactic quality to my starter. For me, I want it to taste like yogurt, rather than have a sharp acidity.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Next post will be on temperature and consistency of starter. And what happens when you use whole wheat or rye flour. Kay?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Photo credit: Modernist Bread&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Juliet Kelson</name></author><summary type="html">It isn't just flour, water and yeast. In fact, one of the most important components growing in that gruel is the microflora-- a spectrum of lactobacillus bacterium, that gives unique flavor, acidity, increased shelf life, and greater digestibility to your bread. But is there too much of a good thing?</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Are We There Yet?</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2020/04/13/are-we-there-yet.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Are We There Yet?" /><published>2020-04-13T20:45:13-07:00</published><updated>2020-04-13T20:45:13-07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2020/04/13/are-we-there-yet</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2020/04/13/are-we-there-yet.html">&lt;p&gt;How can I tell if it’s ripe? See the fine bubbles on the surface and the gentle creasing? Those are good indications. I use these visuals, volume (notice it is something where I can measure the volume easily), and time to determine sourdough maturity. Some people say to see if the starter floats in cool water. I think this is a really bad way to assess ripeness— once you have significant carbon dioxide production from the yeast, it will float for some time on either side of that perfect fermentation window ledge. Don’t fall out!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/img/posts/buckets.jpeg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These two starters have equal weight and proportion, but the one on the left is whole wheat flour. Yeast and bacteria love the added minerals that the bran in whole grain flours provide. As such, the whole wheat starter will ferment more quickly, even though the proportions, temperature and environments are identical.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/img/posts/starter_tops.jpeg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I maintain a few different cultures: liquid white, rye, and sometimes stiff white. But I set whole grain starters up for specific use. They’re just too needy (as in: need to be fed more often). The magic is in the fermentation. Bran is inherently bitter— like me. When you ferment it, it becomes sweet— like me. Whole grain flours also have less capacity to trap gas, creating interesting bubbles (alveoles) and lightness in a final loaf.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Juliet Kelson</name></author><summary type="html">How can I tell if it’s ripe? See the fine bubbles on the surface and the gentle creasing? Those are good indications. I use these visuals, volume (notice it is something where I can measure the volume easily), and time to determine sourdough maturity. Some people say to see if the starter floats in cool water. I think this is a really bad way to assess ripeness— once you have significant carbon dioxide production from the yeast, it will float for some time on either side of that perfect fermentation window ledge. Don’t fall out!</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">A Million Miracles</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2020/04/03/a-million-miracles.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="A Million Miracles" /><published>2020-04-03T20:46:13-07:00</published><updated>2020-04-03T20:46:13-07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2020/04/03/a-million-miracles</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2020/04/03/a-million-miracles.html">&lt;p&gt;I thought you could use some positive news in these uncertain days. I’ve been busy since the last update. I’ve zigzagged the country teaching professional classes, met with the rest of the board to plan for the Bread Bakers Guild for the year, and toured a zillion bakeries to get inspiration and better solidify my own plans. The generosity of the baking community continues to take my breath away.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/img/posts/million_miracles.jpeg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&quot;font-size:60%&quot;&gt;The incredible team at Sun Street Breads in Minneapolis. Solveig Tofte, owner of Sun Street, Chair of the Bread Bakers Guild of America’s Board, and all around badass insistent I come study her bakery and others. Thank goodness she did!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/img/posts/this_machine.jpeg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&quot;font-size:60%&quot;&gt;Brake Bread was among many bakeries I visited in Minneapolis and St. Paul. Thank you for your candor and enthusiasm.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/img/posts/moxie_baking.jpeg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While visiting Moxie Baking Co in Louisville, CO, my friend and hero Andy Clark told me that a million miracles are coming my way. And don’t you know, he’s exactly right? From the farmer and miller who have been delivering local flour to me to the baker that volunteered to reconfigure my pro forma-- I feel so incredibly fortunate for the new and old friends who have reached out to provide guidance as I learn all of the things I didn’t know that I don’t know.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/img/posts/sandwich.jpeg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&quot;font-weight:bold; font-size:125%&quot;&gt;Sandwich Witchery&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&quot;font-weight:bold&quot;&gt;The food at Moxie is off the rails. Having an enthusiastic team, high quality ingredients, and endless creativity helps!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So here’s where we are today. On my way home from a wheat trial with the Artisan Grain Collaborative and University of Wisconsin Madison, my gig work for the next three months was all cancelled and I got notice that the farmers markets would be delayed.  And then the texts and emails started pouring in from customers that couldn’t find bread, or really needed something delicious to sooth their anxieties. I immediately started baking, opening our wood-fired oven months early and without a plan. Certainly this activity soothes me too. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We are currently open for contactless pick-up three days a week. Our limited menu is posted on our Facebook group and updated on our website.  Since we can’t have the staff we normally have, quantities are limited. We appreciate your patience as we figure out new systems and open our Bread Shed to the public—something we never intended to do. It has been gratifying to nourish the community and I appreciate how considerate people have been with respecting social distancing. We will continue to bake for you from the Bread Shed for as long as we need to and as long as we stay healthy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the meantime, I’ve signed a lease, received my mechanical drawings from the architect, and today I got a message from the oven manufacturer letting me know they have finished building our new oven. I am currently looking for contractors; so if you know someone, feel free to point me in their direction.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Juliet Kelson</name></author><summary type="html">I thought you could use some positive news in these uncertain days. I’ve been busy since the last update. I’ve zigzagged the country teaching professional classes, met with the rest of the board to plan for the Bread Bakers Guild for the year, and toured a zillion bakeries to get inspiration and better solidify my own plans. The generosity of the baking community continues to take my breath away.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Kickstarter Is Here!</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2020/01/10/kickstarter.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Kickstarter Is Here!" /><published>2020-01-10T19:46:13-08:00</published><updated>2020-01-10T19:46:13-08:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2020/01/10/kickstarter</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2020/01/10/kickstarter.html">&lt;p&gt;After much hemming and hawing and hand-wringing, we have launched our &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.kickstarter.com/projects/bootlegv2/it-takes-a-village-to-raise-an-oven?ref=user_menu&quot;&gt;Kickstarter&lt;/a&gt;. We hope that you will support our short-term project today, so we can bake for you in the long-term!&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Juliet Kelson</name></author><summary type="html">After much hemming and hawing and hand-wringing, we have launched our Kickstarter. We hope that you will support our short-term project today, so we can bake for you in the long-term!</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">If We Build It, Will You Come?</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2020/01/05/if-we-build-it.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="If We Build It, Will You Come?" /><published>2020-01-05T19:46:13-08:00</published><updated>2020-01-05T19:46:13-08:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2020/01/05/if-we-build-it</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2020/01/05/if-we-build-it.html">&lt;p&gt;After months of revisions, loads of input and lots of hand-wringing, our business plan and projections are ready to go. We have found a wonderful neighborhood space in Skokie. It’s on the same street that our family worked with the Village to get the speed limit lowered and a bike lane installed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We are working with our architect to design a space that is efficient for our business and comfortable for our customers that want to come in, visit, enjoy the aroma, and experience the art of baking.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Juliet Kelson</name></author><summary type="html">After months of revisions, loads of input and lots of hand-wringing, our business plan and projections are ready to go. We have found a wonderful neighborhood space in Skokie. It’s on the same street that our family worked with the Village to get the speed limit lowered and a bike lane installed.</summary></entry></feed>